Inventory to the John Nicholas Beffel Papers TAM.055
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series III: Writings by Beffel
  - "Series" VIII: Index to Correspondents (alphabetical)
    T., Louise // TALEATH, D. L. // TATTY, John See: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 4 (Subject Section) // TEACHER // TEASDALE, Sara (Filsinger) // *TEICHNER, Miriam // TERZANI, Athos See Also: Terzani Case; Tresca Memorial Committee No. 2 (Subject Section) // THOMAS, Dr. Evan // *THOMAS, Norman See Also: Memorial Issue of Controcorrente; Terzani Case Correspondence; Tresca Memorial Committee (Subject Section) // THOMPSON, Mrs. E. S. L. // *THOMPSON, Fred. THOMPSON, R. C. See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // THOMPSON, William G. See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // TIPPY, Worth M. See: Ford and Suhr (Subject Section) // TISLER, C. C. // TOM // TOMPKINS, Howard (For Roger Baldwin) See: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 2 (Subject Section) // TORRE, Marie See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 21 (Subject Section) // TRACHTENBERG, Alexander // TRAUBEL, Ann and Horace // *TRAVAGLIO, Ester Hartz // TRESCA, Beatrice See: TRESCA, Carolo // *TRESCA, Carlo (on letter in Italian, dated April, 1942) See Also: DIGGINS, John; SANDBERG, Carl; Tresca Memorial Committee (Subject Section) // *TRUNCK, Irene // TUCKER, Peg // TURNER, Miss // TURNER, John I // TYLER, Gus // TYLER, Gertrude
    UFERS ? (Ufer ?), Walter //
    *VALENTI, Girolamo (obituary) (Including material about a proposed book by Sylvia Miller Valenti about her husband) // VALENTI, Sylvia Miller See: DI MARCO, Mario; VALENTI, Girolamo // VANDEVEER, George F. See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // *VELEKER, Wilma Haywood // VILLARD, Oswald Garrison See Also: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 2 (Subject Section)
    *W., Margaret See Also: United Office and Professional Workers of America (Subject Section) // WAGNER, Robert F. // WALKER, Stanley // *WALLING, Anna Strunsky and Georgia // WALSH, M.J. // WAN NIERSTROM, Doris See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence 'No. 3 (Subject Section) // WARBASSE, James // WATKINS, Ann // WATTS, Rowland See: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 1 (Subject Section) WEBSTER, Priscilla // (+)WEHDE, Albert (Including material relating to his book Since Leaving Home; a second folder contains his artistic work and photographs) // WEINSTEIN, David // WEINSTOCK, Harris See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // WELINDER, P. J. See: Centralia Correspondence Nos. I and 2 (Subject Section) // WESTMAN // WHALEY, P. H. // WHITE, Jack See Also: United Libertarian Organization (Subject Section) // WHITE, Grant // WINESTINE, Belle Fligleman // WOLF, Kathryn // WOLFE, Bertram D. // WOLHEIM, Louis // WOOD, Charles W. // WOOD, Leone // WOODWARD, Frederick A. // *WORTHINGTON, Dorothy // WRIGHT, Palmer
    YELENSKY, B. (Boris ?) See: Box 23 // YOUNG, A. Cameron // *YOUNG, Art (Including material relating to his autobiography) See Also: COLLAT, Ruth; COPLEY, Frank B.; DAVIN, Tom; FURMAN, Lee
    ZAPATA, Modesto // ZERNER, Charles // *ZIMMERMAN, Mary (Including letters to Louise Friese and a photograph)
    - Index to Correspondents: A, undated
    - Index to Correspondents: B, undated
    - Index to Correspondents: C
    - Index to Correspondents: D
    - Index to Correspondents: E
    - Index to Correspondents: F
    - Index to Correspondents: G
    - Index to Correspondents: H
      *H. (Hodgins?), K. (Katherine?), See Also: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // HAAS, Walter F. (To Donald Harrington) // HAESSLER, Carl // *HALL, Covington ("Covami") HANNA, Rosa Laddon, See: Federated Press (Subject Section) // HANSEN, Harry // HARDMAN, Virginia Mishnun // HAROLD // HARRINGTON, Donald, See: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 2 (Subject Section) // HARRINGTON, Michael // HARRIS, Frank // HAVEL, Nora // HAWKINS?, Carter H. // HAYES, Arthur Garfield (From Theresa H. Saper, secretary to Mr. Hayes), See Also: Terzani Case Correspondence (Subject Section) // HAYWOOD, William B., See: BARRY, Dick; BRAZIER, Richard; BUCKLEY, John; LETCHEM, E.W.; LUNDOFF, John M.; VELEKER, Wilma Haywood // HAZLETT, Dr. William // HEATON, Dennis (Jr.) // HEBER // HENNACY, Ammon, See: League for Mutual Aid Anniversary Dinner (Subject Section) // HENRIETTE // HERTZBERG, Sidney // HEUBSCH, E. W., See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 1; Job and Job hunting (Subject Section) // Hill, Joe, See: THOMPSON, Fred // HILL, Walter // HILLSTROM, Joseph, See, Thompson, Fred // HILSON, Maxine ("Kid") // HODGINS, Katherine H. // HOGAN, Hon. Frank S., See: Tresca Memorial Committee Nos. I and 6 (Subject Section) // HOKE, Calm Morrison (Including a photograph) // HOLCOMBE // HOLLAND, Tom, See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // HOLLOD, Dr. Maurice L., See Also: Ferrer School (Subject Section) // HOPE, Mary (Pseudonym for Mary Ahlquist) // HOPKINS, Arthur // HORNE, Lena // HOWIE, Michael // HUMBLE, Marian? // HUMPHREY, Mary // *HU7NTINGTON, Catherine.
    - Index to Correspondents: I
    - Index to Correspondents: J
    - Index to Correspondents: K
    - Index to Correspondents: L
    - Index to Correspondents: M
      MC________, Zack // MC ARTHUR, Fred J., See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // McCAFFREY, Msgr. Joseph J. // McDONALD, Lucy, See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // McFEE, William // McGILL, Andrew (Pseudonym), See: MORLEY, Christopher // McGIVNEY, John, See: Centralia Correspondence No. I (Subject Section) // McGURRIN, Hon. James // McINTYRE, 0. 0. // McLEAN, Alex, See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // McKNIGHT, Charles, See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // McNAMARA, Hon. Edmund L., See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 3 (Subject Section) // *MC SWIGAN, Marie // *MAHLER, Herbert (Obituaries), See Also: Kentucky Miners Defense Correspondence (Subject Section) // MARER, Nat, See: League for Mutual Aid 1960s and Anniversary Dinner; Ferrer School (Subject Section) // MARI // MARIAN // MARKS, A. J. // MARTEL, Frank X., See: Centralia Correspondence No. 1 (Subject Section) // MARTIN, Alberto // MARTIN, Anna // MARTIN, Pete // MARY // MARY AND NELL (Curry family? Relatives of Beffel) // MATTHEWS, Ben A., See: Tresca Memorial Correspondence No. 5 (Subject Section) // MATTESON, Mrs. Lee (Re: Nell) // MAUCHENHEIM, C. Egan // MAURER, Meyer Emil, See: Terzani Case Correspondence (Subject Section) // MAURICE // MAY (Diana Truesdale?) // MAYNARD, Allen, See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // MAYNARD, Louis R., See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // MEAD, Dr. Kate Campbell Hurd // MEAGAN (Meager?), Anna // MEITLEIN, Beatrice // MEITLEIN, Rose // MELTZER, Joseph, See: Memorial Issue of Controcorrente General Correspondence (Subject Section) // *MENCKEN, H. L. // MERLING, Sam, See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // MICHENER, Jean Duval (Mrs. A. H.) // MILGRAM, Morris // MILHOLLAND, Mrs. John E. (Including a letter to Jane Burr re: Milholland) // MILLER, G. E., See: FRESCO, Mauricio // MILLET, Pauline // MILLIGAN, Carl G. // MINA // MINGANA, A. // MINOR, Robert // MIRAVITELLES, Jaume, See: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 4 (Subject Section) // MITCHELL, Gordon, See: League for Mutual Aid 1930s (Subject Section) // MODESTO, Zapata // MOFFAT, Alexander J. // MOLISANI, E. Howard, See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 3 (Subject Section) // MOLONEY, Francis X. // MONTANA, Vanni, See: Tresca Memorial Committee No. 5 (Subject Section) // *MOONEY, TOM (Including two letters from Rena Mooney) // MONOLDI, P.? (Peo) // MOORE, Fred H. // MOORE, Lola D. // MOORE, Rob // MOORE, U. G., See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // MORAN, T. J., See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // MOREHOUSE, D. F. // MORGAN, T. S. // MORLEY, Christopher (Including a letter from Herman Abromson) // MORO, Guilio de // MOUDY, Mr. W.F., See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // MURRAY, Pauli, See: League for Mutual Aid 1940s (Subject Section) // MUSMANNO, Hon. Michael A., See: Memorial Issue of Controcorrente; Sacco and Vanzetti (Subject Section).
    - Index to Correspondents: N
      NAELY, Marshall // *NARETTY, Vera NEFF, Fanny (Re: Earl J. Yeager) // NEARING, Scott See: League for Mutual Aid Anniversary Dinner (Subject Section) // NELSON, Louis See: Sacco and Vanzetti Correspondence No. 3 (Subject Section) // NELSON, Walter M. See: MOORE, Fred H. NICHIOLS, Esta V. (Mrs. Dudley) // NICHOLS, Dr. John H. // NIELSEN ?, Jens // NOAH, Robert M. // NOLAN, P. J. See: Centralia Correspondence No. 2 (Subject Section) // NOMAD, Max (Including an incomplete manuscript of Nomad book) // NORTHROP, Miss Agnes F. See: League for Mutual Aid 1940s (Subject Section) // *NORWOOD, Rose.
    - Index to Correspondents: O
      0., Jessie (Oakley) // OAKLEY ?, Jessie // ODER or ODEN, Fremont // O'DONNEL, Tom C. // *O'CONNER, Harvey // *O'CONNER, Tom // O'HARE, Frank P // O'NEILL, Eugene // ORCUTT, Jessie // OSCAR OUTTIER, Alexis.
    - Index to Correspondents: P
    - Index to Correspondents: Q
    - Index to Correspondnets: R
    - Index to Correspondents: S
    - Index to Correspondents: T
    - Index to Correspondents: U
      UFERS ? (Ufer ?), Walter
    - Index to Correspondents: V
    - Index to Correspondents: W
    - Index to Correspondents: Y
    - Index to Correspondents: Z
- Series IV: Writings by Others
  - Contains: (Box 19)
    Paul Crouch: Includes part of a manuscript by Crouch, a well known American communist, Broken Chains" later entitled "Bondage Broken"; an article by Crouch, "Top A Bomb Scientist Was a Communist," and other material relating to Crouch, including correspondence; Ennes Ellae: A complete autobiography in manuscript form by
    Ennes Ellae: A complete autobiography in manuscript form entitled "A Grain of Sand -- A Drop of Water," edited by Beffel (281 pp.). Ellae was a Dutch emigrant to the U.S. who became involved with the I.W.W. in California
    Alice M. Gray: Manuscript, including proof sheets of a draft of sorts
    Ellen Leonard: Manuscript of "Three Days of Terror"
    W.H. Long: 2 copies; one incomplete of a manuscript "Sane Sex Life and Sane Sex Living."
  - Contains: (Box 20)
    Helen Parkhurst: Complete ms. of Parkhurst's "Child World"
    Louise Andrus Rogers: Contains 2 manuscripts: "Of Sunken Gold," a film score; “No Encores,” a play: and a few letters.
  - Contains: (Box 21)
    Contains the fragile original of Harry Kelley's manuscript "Roll Back the Years: Odyssey of a Libertarian," edited by Beffel. Kelly was a well known anarchist and co founder of the Ferrer colony in Stelton, N.J.
    NOTE: patrons must use the user photocopy of this manuscript which is housed in boxes 26 and 27.
    For additional information, see the subject folder "Ferrer School" in Box 11. (This manuscript contains some photocopies from the Beffel collection at Wayne State University, Archives of Labor History and Urban Affairs.)
  - Contains: (Box 22)
    Contains manuscript (complete?) of G.P. Maximoff's book of Bakunin's works, edited by Beffel, titled Bakunin's Political Philosophy: His writings on Scientific Anarchism. The manuscript also includes a biographical sketch of Bakunin by Max Nettlau and an introduction by Rudolf Rocker. Also included are a few letters to and from Olga Maximoff Urkevich, Rudolf Rocker and Boris Yelensky.
- Series V. Family Files (unprocessed)
  - Contains: unprocessed material (Box 23)
  - Contains: unprocessed material (Box 24)
  - Contains: unprocessed materal (Box 25)
- Series VI: User photocopies from Series IV (Writings by Others)
  - Contains: User photocopy (part 1) of Harry Kelley's manuscript “Roll Back the Years: Odyssey of a Libertarian,” edited by Beffel. (Box 26)
  - Contains: User photocopy (part 2) of Harry Kelley's manuscript “Roll Back the Years: Odyssey of a Libertarian,” edited by Beffel. (Box 27)
- Series VII: Addendum (unprocessed -- boxes 28-32)